CARLOS CUÉLLAR

(661) 717-8201 hola@carloscuellar.net www.carloscuellar.net

9210 NE Woodridge St. Vancouver, WA 98664

Profile

I am an Interaction Designer with an industrial design background and some love for front-end web development. I have been creating experiences that simplify users' lives for more than eleven years.

I am comfortable working in Agile development environments, managing multiple tasks and setting goals for a project. I benefit from discovering new approaches and constantly learning from my colleagues.

Experience

UX Designer at Goldstar Events, Inc. (May 2015 - Present)

As an Interaction Designer at Goldstar I work on different projects for customers, ticket suppliers and company employees. I collaborate with cross functional teams using often a complete design process (user research, whiteboarding, sketching, wireframes, user flows, prototypes, final comps).

- Design of tools for ticket suppliers so they can manage and promote their inventory in our system.
- Design of mobile first solutions for final customers, including a new seating chart UI for checkout.
- Creation of add-ons for partners like Eventbrite.
- User research: conduct interviews to customers, suppliers and employees, organize remote and in-person usability testings, creation of personas.

UI Designer at Lightspeed Systems (July 2012 - March 2015)

- Design of cross-platform solutions for My Big Campus, a K-12 learning management system, including Android, iOS, Windows 8 and Web apps.
- Implementation of semantic markup and concise and scalable CSS for different products.
- Creation of a live style guide used across several web products and followed by the rest of the developers in the company.
- Design of Classroom Orchestrator, a product used by teachers in order to monitor students' computers in real time.

UI Designer at HP AgriSystems (November 2011 - July 2012)

Creation of visual identity, design of interfaces and front-end development for horsepower.com, an ag-oriented e-commerce website.

Web Designer at Micrographic Web Design (January 2008 - August 2011)

This was my little digital shop in Valencia. We created corporate websites for hospitals, wineries and other midsize companies and we collaborated with several local organizations.

Web Designer at Katana Red (November 2006 - January 2008)

Design of interfaces and front-end development at a digital agency, with special attention to in-house projects (online communities and e-commerce sites).

Academic Education

Universitat Jaume I (Castelló, Spain) — Degree in Technical Engineering in Industrial Design (2001-2005)

Non-Academic Education

- Interaction Design Training, Cooper U; Portland, Oregon
- Interaction Design: Beyond the Wireframe, Future Insights Live; Las Vegas,
 Nevada
- Accessibility and usability Workshop, Fundación OVSI; Valencia, Spain
- SEO Workshop, Infonomia; Barcelona, Spain
- Product Design Workshop, Modoloco; Milan, Italy

Skills

Front-end web development skills: HTML, CSS/Sass, Javascript/jQuery, Git, CMS integration.

Prototyping and design software: Sketch, Omnigraffle, Adobe Suite, Invision, Framer.